Guide to the Primary Writing records, 1973-2019 MS2393
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Phyllis Rosenzweig personal correspondence with writers, 1982-2012; MS2393 Series 2
  - Joan Retallack, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Rod Smith, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - David Sternbach, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Fiona Templeton, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Ann Vickery, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Diane Ward [1/2], Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - File 45/46 Diane Ward [2/2], Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Diane Ward Writing, 1998-2012; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hannah Weiner, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Bernard Welt, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Terence Winch, Undated; MS2393 Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- DC small press publications, 1973-1991; MS2393 Series 3
  This series contains publications, monographs and magazine, of small presses located in Washington DC as well as drafts, notes, and correspondence for the publication Intraview which was intended for inclusion in an issue of The Difficulties. The material dates from 1973-1988.
  - D.C. Small Press publications, 1973-1991; MS2393 Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    List of publications: Jim Brodey. Unless, Jawbone, 1977. Jawbone Press was edited by Doug Lang Tina Darragh. Exposed Faces. A.BACUS No. 4 (July 1984) P. Inman, U.S.A., Dry Imager Publications, 1975. Prose. Cover by Doug Lang. P. Inman. Backbite. A.BACUS No. 1 (January 1984) P. Inman. Waver. A.BACUS No. 18 (May 1, 1986) P. Inman. Uneven Development, Jimmy's House of Knowledge, 1984. Cover by Rebecca Levenson. Inscription to Phyllis Rosenzweig Doug Lang. Horror Vacui. Hot Bird Mfg (ed. Ray DiPalma), v.1, no.18 (April 1991) Diane Ward. Text for "Beating A Wooden Fish," for an installation by Tad Wanveer, Washington Project for the Arts, December 4-29, 1979 Terence Winch. Rooms. Hot Bird Mfg (ed. Ray DiPalma), v.1, no.1 (February 1991). Inscribed to Phyllis Rosenzweig
    Titanic Books Publications: Titanic Books was edited by Terence Winch, Bernard Welt, Diane Ward and Doug Lang Kenward Elmslie. The Alphabet Work. Titanic Books, 1977. Includes portrait of the author by Alex Katz Ted Greenwald. Native Land, Titanic Books, 1977. Includes photo of the author by Andy Grundberg Michael Lally. In the Mood, Titanic Books, 1978. Includes photo of the author by John Gossage
    EEL For (Summer 1977), ed. P Inman, with Tina Darragh, P. Inman, Doug Lang, Diane Ward et al.) Mass Transit: A Magazine of D.C. Poets, No. 1 (Summer 1973), No. 2 (Fall-Winter 1973), No. 3 (January 1974), No. 4 (Spring-Summer1974; various issues include Tim Dlugos, Lynne Dreyer, P. Inman, Michael Lally, Bernard Welt, Terence Winch, et al.); Flyer for Mass Transit and Some of Us Press publication
    The Thursday Book: Selected Poetry from the Dove Readings, Jun 1975. Includes Tina Darragh, Tim Dlugos, P. Inman, Michael Lally, Terence Winch et al.
  - "Intraview"(1988),+ between Tina Darragh, Lynne Dreyer, Joan Retallack, and Phyllis Rosenzweig, 1984-1988; MS2393 Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Note provided by the donor: This was initiated by Joan Retallack in response to a request from Tom Beckett for contributions to an intended issue of The Difficulties devoted to writers' interviews (never published); drafts, notes and correspondence, 1985-88, from prior meetings of the four of us at Joan Retallack's house; a copy of a draft sent from Tina to Phyllis, of a paper by Charles Bernstein on Ezra Pound, delivered at MLA conference, Washington, DC,12/29/1984. *"Intraview" is referred to in Ann Vickery. Leaving Lines of Gender: A Feminist Genealogy of Language Writing (Hanover and London: Wesleyan University Press, 2000), 24.
- Doug Lang correspondence and publications, 1977-2013; MS2393 Series 4
  This series are something of a mini-archive containing correspondence, original publications of early work, and unpublished texts. Doug Lang is an influential poet and the catalyst for the formation of a close-knit community of writers in and around D.C. and beyond. A more complete archive of his work is housed in the John Jay Burns Library, Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA.
  - Doug Lang, 1977-2013; MS2393 Series 4 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Note from donor: Miscellaneous correspondence from and about Doug Lang; reviews of his book, Dérangé by Mike Zito and Terence Winch; typescript of "The Great Dismal Swamp" by Doug Lang, published in OR, Fall 2003; original typescript of "So Jah She" a collaboration between Doug Lang, Rebecca Levenson and Diane Ward, 12/27/81 for P.R.; original typescript of "Too Marvelous for Words" by Doug Lang (nd) inscribed to Phyllis Rosenzweig; photo of Doug Lang by Mary Swift; photo by Doug Lang (?) of Phyllis Rosenzweig and Terence Winch, and Tad Wanveer and Bernard Welt [Mary Swift was the co-editor of Washington Review of the Arts, for which many of us wrote; Becky Levenson, a painter, was Doug's long-time girlfriend; Tad Wanveer, a sculptor, was Diane Ward's boyfriend; Diane Ward, Bernard Welt, and Terence Winch are poets whose correspondence is elsewhere in these files];typescript for "dérangé"; typescript of Doug Lang's graduation speech for the Corcoran class of 1981; syllabus for Doug Lang's Corcoran class, "History of Recorded Jazz," February 1982,with scribbled notes by Phyllis Rosenzweig; typescript of "Kendall Buster and the Expanding Universe of American Art," (1983?) published in Washington Review of the Arts (?); photocopy of "Orwell: 1984 and 1984: The Future Arrives," by Doug Lang in Review, November-December 1983; announcements and a brochure with an essay by Doug Lang for ACE exhibitions, a series of artist organized exhibitions in a former t-shirt warehouse, c.1983 (?); press release by Doug Lang [unsigned] for an exhibition of photographs by Sandra Rottmann at the Embassy of Peru, November 1999; announcement of and texts by Phyllis Rosenzweig and Diane Ward for Doug Lang's retirement celebration, May 1, 2013; typescript of "Daphne's Delight" (?) (nd) short fiction by Doug Lang; typescripts of "Karma Sestina," "Formal Sestina," and "Domestic Sestina," published in Primary Writing #10, 4/97(April 1997); c. 25 pages of typed and Xeroxed unpublished poems, and one short story, by Doug Lang; critical essay,"P. Inman U.S.A. /The Poetics of Defamiliarization" (n.d.).
  - Doug Lang, 1977-2013; MS2393 Series 4 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Separated Materials
    Note from donor:
    Published work by Doug Lang, many mimeographed and published in very small press editions and locally distributed:
    Doug Lang: an emblamatic life of universal dimensions: 7 postcards for Diane Ward.(published as Hot Shot, see below).
    Hot Shot,for Diane Ward (Jawbone), 1977
    Magic Fire Chevrolet (Titanic Books), 1980, and review of it by Art Lange, in Washington Review of the Arts, 7/3, October-November 1981. MFC includes: Sizzle; MacDonald, Pa.; Tom Raworth X's Out a Few; The Depression; Chemical Life; Love & Meat; Nerves; 333; Out of Nowhere; The Body of Con Ed; Buddha Ha-ha; Cubop City; The Language of Love; The Americans; October Moon; Xa; Lester Leaps Out; and Ozone Park.
    Lumbering & Tingling: Sonnets. Self-published. (Bard 1989): Ipanema Sonnet; Formica Sonnet; Corinna Sonnet; Melancholia Sonnet; MICA Sonnet; 2 Sonnets, for Glynis & Liz;2 Sonnets, for Joan & Elaine.
    Horror Vacui (To Corinna Heumann). Self-published, 1991. Visual texts.
    Metro Text. For Tad Wanveer. Self-published, n.d.: Milk Duds, for Ted Greenwald; Memphis, for Phyllis Rosenzweig; D.C. (Is this your dog?); Café (I don't want to go there/There are people there/ I don't want to see there); Atomic Sonnet; Bridge in the Rain, Kimono, Face, and Blue Life, for Lyn Hejinian, with Diane Ward; Metro Text; Hard Times, for Terence Winch,; and two illustrations. In blue plastic folder.